1
00:00:00,630 --> 00:00:01,470
Hello.

2
00:00:01,470 --> 00:00:04,200
So what I'm gonna do in
this video alongside you

3
00:00:04,200 --> 00:00:07,290
is explore using ChatGPT,

4
00:00:07,290 --> 00:00:10,530
which I'm sure many of you have heard of.

5
00:00:10,530 --> 00:00:13,740
So the first question is,
why is it called ChatGPT?

6
00:00:13,740 --> 00:00:15,930
Well, the GPT part stands for

7
00:00:15,930 --> 00:00:20,190
Generative Pre-trained Transformer.

8
00:00:20,190 --> 00:00:21,630
And I guarantee you

9
00:00:21,630 --> 00:00:24,630
that it wasn't some big branding exercise

10
00:00:24,630 --> 00:00:26,370
to say, what would be the most easy thing

11
00:00:26,370 --> 00:00:27,630
for people to remember?

12
00:00:27,630 --> 00:00:30,660
It really is just a description
of the underlying technology

13
00:00:30,660 --> 00:00:32,850
of the AI technology it's based on,

14
00:00:32,850 --> 00:00:34,650
and it just kind of stuck.

15
00:00:34,650 --> 00:00:37,290
And the company that makes it, OpenAI,

16
00:00:37,290 --> 00:00:39,180
I think just stuck with it.

17
00:00:39,180 --> 00:00:41,130
Now the other thing I wanna point out is,

18
00:00:41,130 --> 00:00:44,700
there's a difference between
the applications using the AI

19
00:00:44,700 --> 00:00:49,140
and then the AI models, the
generative AI models themselves.

20
00:00:49,140 --> 00:00:51,480
ChatGPT is an application,

21
00:00:51,480 --> 00:00:53,250
and you can see in my account,

22
00:00:53,250 --> 00:00:55,830
I can pick different models to use.

23
00:00:55,830 --> 00:00:58,200
So I could use GPT-3.5,

24
00:00:58,200 --> 00:00:59,100
which is the version,

25
00:00:59,100 --> 00:01:02,520
if someone were to just
start using ChatGPT for free,

26
00:01:02,520 --> 00:01:03,420
they'll get access to.

27
00:01:03,420 --> 00:01:05,340
And that's the version
that was first launched,

28
00:01:05,340 --> 00:01:07,410
although I think they've
improved on it since then.

29
00:01:07,410 --> 00:01:10,830
And then there is the
more advanced version,

30
00:01:10,830 --> 00:01:14,340
which is based off of the GPT-4 model,

31
00:01:14,340 --> 00:01:18,180
which is much more complex,
uses a lot more computation,

32
00:01:18,180 --> 00:01:21,570
and you have to pay money in
order to get access to that.

33
00:01:21,570 --> 00:01:23,040
But we'll take a look at that in a second.

34
00:01:23,040 --> 00:01:27,540
But let me just go with
essentially the free version.

35
00:01:27,540 --> 00:01:29,670
And the Chat part's a
little bit more obvious,

36
00:01:29,670 --> 00:01:31,260
you can chat with it.

37
00:01:31,260 --> 00:01:34,140
So for example, I could say,

38
00:01:34,140 --> 00:01:38,220
What does GPT stand for?

39
00:01:38,220 --> 00:01:41,130
And so we could do the types of things

40
00:01:41,130 --> 00:01:43,500
that you might have before done with say,

41
00:01:43,500 --> 00:01:45,330
a Google or a Bing search.

42
00:01:45,330 --> 00:01:46,163
So it says,

43
00:01:46,163 --> 00:01:48,600
"GPT stands for generative
pre-trained transformers.

44
00:01:48,600 --> 00:01:50,070
It's a type of artificial
intelligence model

45
00:01:50,070 --> 00:01:51,120
developed by OpenAI,

46
00:01:51,120 --> 00:01:54,960
specifically designed for
natural language processing tasks

47
00:01:54,960 --> 00:01:57,630
such as language generation translation,

48
00:01:57,630 --> 00:01:59,430
question answering and more."

49
00:01:59,430 --> 00:02:01,710
Okay. And I would guess that
if you did a web search,

50
00:02:01,710 --> 00:02:03,870
you could probably find
some text like that.

51
00:02:03,870 --> 00:02:06,270
Well, that might be kind of interesting.

52
00:02:06,270 --> 00:02:08,400
But what if we don't really understand

53
00:02:08,400 --> 00:02:09,330
what is talking about?

54
00:02:09,330 --> 00:02:11,850
What do they mean by
natural language processing

55
00:02:11,850 --> 00:02:13,620
or language generation?

56
00:02:13,620 --> 00:02:16,450
And say, "Can you explain it

57
00:02:17,490 --> 00:02:21,837
like you would to a 5-year-old?"

58
00:02:24,397 --> 00:02:27,660
"Of course, imagine GPT,
like a super smart robot

59
00:02:27,660 --> 00:02:29,220
that loves to talk and write.

60
00:02:29,220 --> 00:02:30,420
GPT stands for."

61
00:02:30,420 --> 00:02:32,100
And it tells us again,

62
00:02:32,100 --> 00:02:33,637
but we can just call it GPT for short.

63
00:02:33,637 --> 00:02:35,610
"Now this robot has learned a lot

64
00:02:35,610 --> 00:02:37,110
about how people talk and write

65
00:02:37,110 --> 00:02:38,490
by reading tons and tons of books,

66
00:02:38,490 --> 00:02:39,960
articles and conversations.

67
00:02:39,960 --> 00:02:41,040
It's kind of like,

68
00:02:41,040 --> 00:02:42,780
when you learn new words and sensitives

69
00:02:42,780 --> 00:02:45,240
by listening to your parents,
teachers, and friends.

70
00:02:45,240 --> 00:02:47,700
Once it's learned all this
stuff, you can ask it questions

71
00:02:47,700 --> 00:02:48,960
or tell it to write something,

72
00:02:48,960 --> 00:02:51,270
and it'll use all that learning to come up

73
00:02:51,270 --> 00:02:53,280
with answers or write stories.

74
00:02:53,280 --> 00:02:55,650
It's like having a really clever friend

75
00:02:55,650 --> 00:02:58,200
who knows a lot about words and language."

76
00:02:58,200 --> 00:02:59,400
So that's pretty cool.

77
00:02:59,400 --> 00:03:01,140
Maybe someone, if you did a web search,

78
00:03:01,140 --> 00:03:02,850
would've written a simpler explanation,

79
00:03:02,850 --> 00:03:03,683
maybe they wouldn't.

80
00:03:03,683 --> 00:03:06,810
And now it was just in a
matter of a split second,

81
00:03:06,810 --> 00:03:09,090
able to make something more at our level.

82
00:03:09,090 --> 00:03:14,090
Can you write that in Gen Z slang?

83
00:03:15,667 --> 00:03:19,440
"So this AI buddy has basically
absorbed mad knowledge

84
00:03:19,440 --> 00:03:22,920
by scrolling through endless
texts, articles, and convos,

85
00:03:22,920 --> 00:03:26,340
kind of like how you pick up
slang and memes from your feed.

86
00:03:26,340 --> 00:03:28,620
Once it's soaked up all that juice,

87
00:03:28,620 --> 00:03:31,920
you can hit it up with questions
or ask it to drop some bars

88
00:03:31,920 --> 00:03:35,280
and it'll spit out answers
or write stories like a pro.

89
00:03:35,280 --> 00:03:37,170
It's like having that one friend

90
00:03:37,170 --> 00:03:41,190
who's always on point
with the words and lingo."

91
00:03:41,190 --> 00:03:42,600
That's interesting.

92
00:03:42,600 --> 00:03:47,010
Can you write a poem in the style

93
00:03:47,010 --> 00:03:49,990
of Dr. Seuss

94
00:03:53,347 --> 00:03:54,920
explaining GPT technology?

95
00:03:56,760 --> 00:03:58,160
Let's see what it does here.

96
00:03:59,850 --> 00:04:01,327
So let me scroll up a little bit.

97
00:04:01,327 --> 00:04:03,930
"In the world of words where stories roam,

98
00:04:03,930 --> 00:04:06,300
there's a tech that's
truly in its own zone.

99
00:04:06,300 --> 00:04:08,610
It's called GPT, a linguistic king

100
00:04:08,610 --> 00:04:10,050
with a knack for language.

101
00:04:10,050 --> 00:04:11,640
It can surely sing.

102
00:04:11,640 --> 00:04:13,170
Generative pre-trained transformer,

103
00:04:13,170 --> 00:04:15,540
you see is what GPT stands
for as clever it can be."

104
00:04:15,540 --> 00:04:16,980
So I could go on and on.

105
00:04:16,980 --> 00:04:21,180
Now we could try these
same things with GPT-4.

106
00:04:21,180 --> 00:04:23,430
And in future videos I'll
go into a much more depth

107
00:04:23,430 --> 00:04:26,730
of the real power of something like GPT-4.

108
00:04:26,730 --> 00:04:30,120
But we will in general
get better answers here.

109
00:04:30,120 --> 00:04:33,120
Now what's cool about this GPT-4 access

110
00:04:33,120 --> 00:04:35,910
is it also has DALL-E access,

111
00:04:35,910 --> 00:04:39,240
which is integrating with the ChatGPT,

112
00:04:39,240 --> 00:04:41,340
the ability to generate images.

113
00:04:41,340 --> 00:04:43,680
So for example, I could say,

114
00:04:43,680 --> 00:04:48,680
can you create an image of a horse

115
00:04:51,480 --> 00:04:54,960
made out of bananas?

116
00:04:54,960 --> 00:04:57,120
Now let's see what it generates (laughs)

117
00:04:57,120 --> 00:05:00,330
As you can tell, I don't
plan a lot for this stuff.

118
00:05:00,330 --> 00:05:01,740
Oh, look at that, that's beautiful.

119
00:05:01,740 --> 00:05:03,300
So I sped up how long it took,

120
00:05:03,300 --> 00:05:04,560
but it really didn't take that long.

121
00:05:04,560 --> 00:05:05,490
It took about,

122
00:05:05,490 --> 00:05:09,360
I would guess about five to
10 seconds for it to come out.

123
00:05:09,360 --> 00:05:12,510
But that's a nice looking
horse made out of bananas.

124
00:05:12,510 --> 00:05:14,010
It says, "Here's the image of a horse

125
00:05:14,010 --> 00:05:15,480
made entirely out of bananas.

126
00:05:15,480 --> 00:05:17,850
I hope you find this
creative interpretation

127
00:05:17,850 --> 00:05:20,250
to your liking."

128
00:05:20,250 --> 00:05:21,243
Actually,

129
00:05:22,680 --> 00:05:25,380
can we make

130
00:05:25,380 --> 00:05:29,433
this in the style of Van Gogh?

131
00:05:31,770 --> 00:05:33,120
Let's see what it does now.

132
00:05:35,220 --> 00:05:39,180
Look at that, that's a
nice looking banana horse.

133
00:05:39,180 --> 00:05:41,970
I think I would put that
up on my wall, maybe.

134
00:05:41,970 --> 00:05:43,800
I don't think my wife would let me.

135
00:05:43,800 --> 00:05:46,350
But that's pretty darn impressive,

136
00:05:46,350 --> 00:05:48,870
and I'm just really
scratching the surface here.

137
00:05:48,870 --> 00:05:50,730
But this is for you to get a sense

138
00:05:50,730 --> 00:05:55,200
of what these generative
AI tools are capable of,

139
00:05:55,200 --> 00:05:58,263
and they are really
getting better every day.

