In this video,
we're going to talk about
what artificial intelligence even is.
So to start with that, let's
just break down these words,
artificial and intelligence.
And we could start with intelligence.
What does that mean to you?
Well, for most of us,
we associate intelligence
with things that our brains,
that our minds, are doing.
Things like solving problems,
solving problems,
maybe logic,
maybe playing games,
especially games that involve the mind,
games like chess or checkers,
playing games, making recommendations,
making recommendations.
We could also imagine
things like creativity,
creativity,
making things that have
never existed before,
whether it's a painting
or whether it is a story of some kind.
And I could keep going,
and you could come up with your own list
of what do you associate
with intelligence,
what do you think makes
you or me intelligent?
Now let's think about this
other word here, artificial.
Artificial, and it
comes from the same root
as art or artifact.
It's really something that has been made.
So something made,
something made by humans,
usually by us.
I guess if an alien
civilization made something,
that would also be considered artificial.
You could also view it
as something that would
not exist naturally.
So it doesn't exist naturally,
so, or exist in nature.
So for example, my intelligence,
if you think I'm intelligent,
is natural intelligence.
It exists in nature,
it comes out of a
biological system, my brain,
while what we're gonna
talk about in a little bit
are things, forms of intelligence
or things that might be
called an intelligence,
that we made, that
doesn't exist in nature.
Now, a lot of y'all have
seen science fiction movies
where there is some type of a robot,
and this is my very quick drawing
of a robot right over here,
that can talk and walk
and do a lot of the things
that we would consider intelligent.
And if robots like that ever exist,
and really every day we're
getting closer and closer,
but if they ever existed,
these are science fiction's images
of what an artificial
intelligence would be.
And it doesn't need to have a body.
You could have something
that you just talk to.
There's science fiction
movies where the spaceship,
you can talk to it and you
have a conversation with it.
And it seems intelligent,
but it was created by man,
it is artificial.
It did not exist in nature by itself.