So, in this
video we're gonna talk about
where we all have artificial
intelligence, or AI,
in our lives.
And so, before I go into
where we're already seeing it
and where we're likely to
start seeing it more and more,
I want you to pause this video
and think if you can think of any places
where artificial intelligence
is already impacting your life.
All right, now let's
think about this together.
So, I'm guessing that many of you
have interacted with a
smartphone of some kind
and you might've said, "Hey, Siri,"
and/or just pressed
this button long enough
and it says, "Well, what do you like?"
And you talk to it.
Well, that is artificial intelligence, AI.
And once again, why is that AI?
Well, it seems intelligent,
it can understand what
you're asking it to do,
it can find you information,
it can do some tasks for you.
So, it seems intelligent and
it was definitely not natural,
it's technology, it was
made by human beings
so it is artificial intelligence.
I'm guessing many of you
might also have interacted
with devices in your house.
You might have once
again said, "Hey, Siri,"
or "Hey, Alexa," or "Google Home,"
or some other type of device
and it starts talking to you
and you say, "What's the
weather going to be today?"
Or, "How far is the sun away from Earth?"
And so, once again, it seems intelligent,
it's able to understand
what you're saying,
it even knows when you're calling on it,
it's kind of creepy that
it's always listening,
and then it's able to do tasks for you.
You might see AI when
you make a web search.
So, if you go to some search engine
and you do a search
for, let's say, shoes,
oftentimes you're going to see a bunch
of ads show up first
and then you're going to see
a bunch of search results.
These results are usually
not just the same results for everyone,
they're based on what some
artificial intelligence
on the search engine side
thinks that you are
most likely to click on.
Now, in the future,
in future videos we'll talk about
how does it know what people
are most likely to click on?
How does it optimize around that?
But you have artificial intelligence
trying to figure out
what to serve up to you.
You might look at some
type of social media app,
which I don't recommend
spending too much time on it,
but it's giving you a
feed of, say, videos,
say, on an app like TikTok,
which, once again, I don't recommend
spending a ton of time on it
because there's literally
an artificial intelligence
in the background that's
trying to feed you the thing
that you are most likely to engage on.
And you might say, "Well,
what's the big deal about that?
I might just get entertained
or whatever else."
But you might also just
get addicted to it,
it just keeps feeding you the things
that it's seeing that
other people like you
are likely to keep wanting to watch.
And it not only might
take up a lot of time
that you could do spending
outside being with real people,
but it's also feeding you ads,
making you want things that
you don't necessarily need.
It could be showing you things
that are affecting your opinions
in maybe the not most constructive way,
maybe ways it's putting you,
it's reinforcing opinions
you already have,
making it harder for you to
see the other points of view.
And so, we have to be very careful,
but that's definitely a place
where we are seeing
artificial intelligence.
We also see it, you might
think about self-driving cars.
If you think about a car, most of us view,
you have to be pretty intelligent
to recognize things on the road,
be able to read street
signs, et cetera, et cetera.
But these cars have a
bunch of sensors on them,
depending on the type of self-driving car
you're thinking about,
where it's able to make
sense of the images
and other types of sensory
input it has around it
and do things that until recently
people would've thought only
a human could drive a car,
but now we actually have technology
that can make sense of it.
Now, these are all places
where we're seeing artificial intelligence
already affecting our lives.
Where is it likely to affect
our lives more and more?
Well, there are applications
that people have already come up with
where maybe you could take a picture
of maybe you have a rash on your skin
and it could maybe help diagnose,
maybe be an assistant to a doctor
or maybe in places where there
aren't doctors help there,
maybe read an x-ray
or any other type of imagery
to understand what's going on.
It could be used to create.
Many of you have seen videos
where that have been created by AI,
you've seen images that
have been created by AI.
So, it's more and more
going to be a creation tool.
You're going to see cases,
and this is obviously something
that we, at Khan Academy,
take very seriously where
it could help you learn.
Tools like Khanmigo, where
which we have at Khan Academy,
where it can act as a tutor.
Not give you the answer, so
I'll just write tutoring here.
Tutoring, it could not
give you the answer,
but help you think about how to get there.
It could be a writing coach.
I guess that's a kind of
tutoring, writing coach.
It could be a teacher's assistant.
I'll just write TA, TA for short,
where it could help a
teacher develop lesson plans,
or grade papers, or
write progress reports.
So, I'll leave you there.
This is just scratching the surface
of where you, one, already
have artificial intelligence
in your life but just
might not realize it,
but it's good you do realize
it 'cause it's out there.
Some of it's useful,
but you have to be
careful with a lot of it,
and it's going to affect your
lives more and more and more
in the years to come.